大家好，这是第三周的
Hello everyone. Uh, this is, uh, week, uh,
开源循环时尚课程。
three open source circular fashion,
我们将进行一个实用教程，
and we are going to have a helpful tutorial, uh,
讲解设计工作流，
for the workflow for, for designing, uh,
由 Claudia Simonelli 讲解开源循环时尚的激光切割设计。
for os circular fashion for laser cutting from Claudius Mon.
大家好 欢迎收看这个新教程
Hello everyone. Welcome to this, uh, new tutorial. Uh,
我们开始分享我的屏幕
we start us sharing my screen and
从我们昨天看到的情况中，
with a little presentation picking up from what we saw yesterday,
还有佐伊的演讲 所以 当然
also from the lecture of Zoe. So, um, of course,
本周的目标将提出一系列，呃，
the objective of this week will be coming up with a series of, uh,
零废料、模块化设计和镶嵌。
zero waste or modular design and de distillations. Uh,
当然会有激光切割
there will be of course, uh, laser cut. Uh,
这些也被称为无缝模式。
these are called also seamless pattern.
他们将会是开源 然后上传到我们的平台上
They will be open source and uploaded afterwards on our platform,
这叫时尚 com
which is called o fashion.com,
你实际上可以浏览，嗯，
where you actually can already browse, um,
各种各样的模式和创作 从前额，
wide range of patterns and creation from previous uh,
如果你点击他们每个人，
students in the Fabric Academy. Uh, if you click on each of them,
你可以看到，嗯， 材料推荐，过程。
you can actually see, um, the materials recommendation, the processes.
所以，这实际上是向其他人学习的方法 下载
So it's actually a way to learn from the others downloading the
并经历这种方式，
pattern, and also experience this kind of way of,
组装和拆卸不同的模块 来创造更大的，嗯，
of assembling and dis assembling different modules to create bigger, um,
进一步创作。
further creations. Uh,
当然，所以你也可以看到新的更新 和新的，嗯，添加。
of course, so you can also see the new updates and the new, um, additions.
我本周也建议
I also suggested during this week, uh,
你们大部分人已经可以拍好照片上传了 呃
most of you will be already able to take nice pictures and upload, uh,
嗯，你的档案和文档图片。
um, your files along with documentation pictures.
我也想从昨天做的那事上接过来
I also want to pick up from what, uh, uh, done yesterday.
当然，这是工作流程。
So of course this is gonna be the workflow. Uh, we're gonna start, uh, also, um,
今天晚些时候用一些软件进行数字设计的实验.
later on today with a couple of software to experiment with digital design.
我们上周还看到 我们主要要使用矢量
We also saw from last week that we're gonna mainly basically use the vectors
既然我们要用激光切割器
since we're gonna use the laser cutter.
这是过去学生的榜样，嗯，
This is an example from past student to see, um,
我们从2D开始 走向真正的装配服装
how from two D we're moving towards a real assembled garment.
这当然是零浪费，我想说，是的，
Uh, this, of course, it's completely zero waste. Uh, I would say, yeah,
软件是一个工作流程问题， 所以它并不真正重要的是，嗯，
software is a matter of workflow, so it doesn't really matter which, um,
基于矢量设计的程序 或三个D建模器 你实际使用，
vector design based program or three D modeler you're actually using,
他们都会带领你，呃，
all of them are gonna lead you, uh,
说到这周的目标 你其实可以
to the objective of the week, let's say. Uh, and you can actually, um,
试着把它们融合在一起，嗯，
try to blend them together and, uh,
创建矢量之间的这种协作，但也创建模型软件.
create this collaboration between Vector, but also the model software.
当然 对于那些更熟悉矢量设计的人来说
So of course, for the ones that are more familiar with vector based design,
我建议接下来使用 Illustrator 或 Inkscape，
I would, I would recommend, uh, to keep going with Illustrator on Inscape,
开源版本，呃，
the open source version, uh,
但从参数模型的角度来说，Fusion其实很有帮助
but also Fusion in terms of parametric modeling actually is helpful
如果我们想开始，呃，呃，
if we want to start, uh, uh,
直接考虑政府的实际规模 所以规模
thinking directly in the real size of the government. So for the scale,
一对一其实是我的建议 当然
one to one is actually, uh, my recommendation and of course,
Rhino或更好的软件 那些已经有点熟悉，
rhino or better software for the ones that are already a little bit familiar,
用这种软件
uh, with this kind of software. Uh,
我想这里的例子苏珊娜 从几年前在法国，呃，
I think the example here of Susanna from a couple of years ago in France, uh,
其实，嗯，
actually, um,
打破所有导致这个步骤，呃，
breaks down all the steps that lead to this, uh,
交织的挂毯
interwoven kind of, um, tapestry. So, um,
我想我们这周的大部分工作 肯定都是为了找到一个伟大的
I think most of our work this week will be definitely on finding a great
灵感
inspiration.
我想说，Ani的其中之一 实际上是最好的例子 同时展示，
And I would say the one of Ani is actually the best example to also showcase,
额...
um,
如何把灵感从纸上 一直转换成零浪费
how this inspiration can be translated from paper all the way to a zero waste,
为激光切割机准备的设计。例如这里，
uh, design from the laser catheter. So, as you can see here, for example,
有一个零平方。
there's a zero squares.
因此，她实际上能够重新设计 在那里，她看到在一个寺庙
So she was actually able to redesign where she saw in a temple
翻译为纸，然后到 感觉最小化所有废物，
translate to paper, and then afterwards onto felt minimizing all the waste,
尽可能多，但是机器时间
uh, as much as possible. But also the machine times,
嗯，我们昨天看到一点点， 有原则背后，
uh, we saw yesterday a little bit, there are the principle behind,
但记住还有...
but it's good to keep in mind that there's are also, um,
它们都互相关联
they all relate to each other.
所以，我们当然在谈论 很多关于零浪费，嗯，
So of course we are talking about a lot about zero waste, um,
模块化时装、镶嵌，以及
modular fashion tessellation, and also, um,
无缝互锁衣服.
seamless interlocking garments.
嗯，他们只是，呃，嗯， 小灵感说话 从昨天到，嗯，
Uh, they're just, uh, um, little inspirations speaking up from yesterday to, um,
仅仅给出一些评论 关于最佳做法，呃，
just give some comments about best practices, uh,
加入，呃， 看去年的学生，例如，
joins, uh, looking at the students of last year, for example,
那是摩尔多瓦的例子 我想我们可以
that was an example from Moldova. Uh, I think we can,
我们可以调整，有时甚至我们有一个非常基本的模式，
we can align how sometimes even we have a very basic pattern,
这其实是自我重复，所以只是一个圆圈。
which is actually a repetition of this itself. So just a circle. Uh,
我们还可以，呃，
we can still, uh,
大量研究如何把这些部件组装在一起 来创建甚至三个D
work a lot on how these pieces can be assembled together to create even three D
结构，或两个D和三个D同时结合。
structures, or two D and three D that combine at the same time.
这里其实很有趣 这个袋子是如何可以关闭自己的。
And here is actually interesting how this bag is actually able to close itself.
我在上面放了一些关键词
Um, I put some keywords here on top. So, uh, for example,
模拟是本周很有帮助的工具
also, uh, simulations are tools that are help quite helpful for this week.
嗯，这是使用，我想，一个矢量软件 例如，
Um, this is using, I guess, a vector software like, for example,
Illustrator和已经在软件里玩过
illustrator and already playing inside the software,
嗯，也是一个方法，
um, is also a way to,
从形状的角度思考 并分配不同的颜色 会引导你，嗯，
to think in terms of shape and assign different colors will lead you to, um,
进一步探索以不同方式配置和
explore further the way in different ways of configure and
重组，呃，你的形状，呃，
reconfigure, uh, the shapes that you have, uh,
分层是另一种技术 所以在这种情况下
layering is another technique. So in this case, um,
我们以前和过去都见过，呃，
we also saw it previously and in the past tutorial, uh,
因此，我们正在从更多的，呃， 让我们说几何形状 变成更多的，嗯，
so we are moving from more, uh, let's say geometrical shape into more, um,
液体和有机物 当然 灵感可以...
fluids and organic ones. So of course, uh, inspirations can be, uh,
还有花本性
also flower nature.
而在这种情况下， 也很有趣 看到如何在一个猫，
And in this case is also interesting to see how in one single cat,
一个单一的旅程 我们可以将两块或多块连在一起
one single journey we can actually interlock two or more pieces together.
这当然也取决于材料的厚度，但是，呃，
It also depends, of course, on the thickness of the material, but also, uh,
在图案上。
on the pattern. Adjo itself, uh,
也想说一个零浪费的方法，嗯，
wanted to say that also a zero waste approach, um,
可用于更大的工作表。例如，
can be applied to a larger sheet. For example,
去年巴塞罗纳有一个例子
there is example of ve from Barcelona of last year, uh,
这当然是完全零 废物不是由不同的模型制造的
where this is of course completely zero waste is not made of different models
在一起，但仍，呃，
together, but still, uh,
有一个单一的图案 然后你可以看到这里的底部，
there is one single pattern then you can see here at the bottom,
只不过...
and it's just, uh, uh,
用激光打印出来 在表上面。
printed out with the laser on top of the sheet.
结果是，呃，
So the result is this, uh,
那种可折叠的结构 你实际上可以穿作为一件裙子。
kind of collapsible structure that you can actually wear as a dress.
嗯，我稍后会分享幻灯片 这样你就可以，呃，
Um, I'll share the slides later so you can actually, uh,
按下链接，查找所附的所有文件。
press on the link and find all the documentation attached.
我觉得骑自行车也是这个星期的关键词
I think upcycling is also a key word for this week,
有个汉宁的例子
and there was an example of Hanin, um,
几年前在这里的科技工作 她骑自行车，嗯，
a couple of years ago here in tech works that she was up cycling, um,
一个非常大的窗帘 从房子 用天鹅绒做 并获得灵感
a very big curtain from the house that was made in velvet and getting inspired
从海洋生物。
from sea creatures.
海洋实际上能够工作，嗯，
And the ocean was actually able to work, um,
试探这种窗帘 还有利用边缘
to testate this kind of curtain. Also using the edge,
不只是前方的图案，
not only just the front of the back of the pattern,
还有厚度本身 来创造这种垂直的，呃，
but also the thickness itself to create this kind of vertical, uh,
配置。因此，如果你探索这个， 例如，在循环时尚，
configuration. So if you explore this, for example, on a circular fashion,
您也可以找到所有不同步骤的小册子。
you can also find the booklet with all the different steps.
如果你可以的话，这个也不错，嗯，
And this is something that can be also nice if you're able to, and, uh,
如果你能在一周内上传
if you manage to upload it during the week,
另一种技术可以和日本艺术家Kigami有关
another technique can be related to the kigami, the Japanese of art,
剪折纸，这是...
of, uh, cutting a folding paper. And this is the,
我认为最好的例子 是由蒂安娜。
I think the best example is given by Tiana.
然后她明显被哈迪德和建筑形状所监视
Then she was clearly spied by the hadid and architectural shapes to
将关节和图案结合起来。所以这里的底部，再次，
combine a joint together with a pattern. So here the bottom, again,
有一个很好的例子，呃，加入。
there is a nice example, uh, of join.
一个模块重复，实际上，嗯，
And one single module repeated can actually, actually, um,
创造这样的契约，呃， 一个有趣的配置，
create this kind of deed, uh, an interesting configuration,
嗯，对于那些已经
um, for the ones that are already
也建议继续探索
also suggest to keep going and explore, uh,
不同的滑动器和可能性。
different sliders and possibility. That was the work of a tool, um,
几年前也从科技公司买的
from tech as well a couple of years ago.
我很高兴看到她...
And I think here is nice to see how she, um,
添加这种密度参数 。
added this kind of parameter of density.
所以她控制着不同目标之间的空间
So she was controlling the space in between the different gons.
再说一次，如果你点击照片， 你会看到，呃，全面探索。
And again, if you click on the picture, you gonna see, uh, the full exploration.
嗯，一个话题 同时，嗯，
Um, one topic also to, um,
说到的服务是 设计联合，
that service to be talking about is to engineer the joint,
比如说 材料的厚度
um, taking top count, for example, the, uh, thickness of the material,
还有你总能改进的形状，嗯，
but also the shape you can always improve, um,
两块是怎样连接在一起的，还是三块.
how the two pieces are connected together, or the three pieces.
所以，这是一个例子 可能你也看到，嗯，
So this is an example of might where you also see, um,
她如何从连接两块 一路应用，嗯，
how she moved from connecting two pieces all the way to apply, um,
然后在一件T恤的不同部分克隆一个单关节 来创造，呃，
and cloning a single joint on different part of one t-shirt to create, uh,
不同的交织配置趋势，不是，呃，
different interwoven configurations trend, not, uh,
完全对称，比如说，从前面或后面。
completely symmatic, for example, from the front or the back. So in this case,
比如说，她把床单当作游乐场
for example, she's using a sheet as a playground.
所以，她已经同意在哪里，
So she has kind of agreed where the,
她可以玩正负的空间。
she can play with positive and negative spaces. Uh,
关节也可以是装饰 我们有很多学生的例子
joints can also be decoration. We have many examples in the students. Um,
我最喜欢的就是这个月亮面孔
a favorite of mine, I think is this one, is the moon faces, uh,
很明显的灵感来自月球
clearly inspired by, um, by the moons.
我觉得很有趣...
And I think it's interesting how, um,
安娜正在翻译和重新设计这种...
Anna in this case was translating and redesigning this kind of, uh,
额...
um,
月球上的配置成一个图案，用作组合.
configuration on the moon into a pattern to be used as a join.
甚至连接更大的床单，
And even connecting bigger sheets together,
比如说，加入也可以和品牌有关
um, joins can also relate to branding, for example.
这是Lara校区的情况，你第一次看到，嗯，
And this is the case of a Lara campus, where you saw on first time, um,
介绍一下 说说讲故事的概念吧
um, introducing, let's say the, um, concept of storytelling. So it's nice.
嗯，我想说画可以 由两个不同的元素塑造。
Uh, I would say the drawing can be shaped by two different element.
例如，我们有一个凹连接件和一个凸连接件。
And we have a female and a male, for example. Um,
他们可以编曲和代表
the moment interlock each other. They're actually able to compose and represent,
额，嗯，
uh, um,
可以在具体部分应用的标志或有趣的设计，
a logo or an interesting design that can be applied in specific parts,
嗯，一个床单，呃，一个小马 和这个案例的例子，呃，
um, of a sheet, uh, of a poncho and example in this case, uh,
鱼或项目的标志，所以那是一只小马，嗯，
a fish or a logo of the project. So that was a pon that was, um,
所以我也给你留下了链接
raising awareness about ocean. So I also leave you the link, uh,
以进一步探索这个故事。
to explore further the story. Uh,
个人网格也可以探索。
personal grids can also be explored. And, um, modular heritage, I think, um,
至少对于这个实验室来说 技术工作是一个话题 我们，
at least for this lab here in tech works is a topic that we,
每年我们探索。
every year we explore.
这是米亚姆在任务期间最后的项目
This is the final project of Miam that was actually born during the assignment
第三个星期，这里，
of the third week. And here's,
所以她把社区带入项目的方式，嗯，
so the way she brings the community inside the project, um,
以数字化的方式重建巴勒斯坦刺绣
recreating the Palestinian embroidery in a more, um, digital way.
比如说，她可以用同一个网格来做其他不同的图案。
So for example, she could use the same grid for, um, other different patterns.
她还设计了，嗯，
And she also crafted, um,
这种藏品显然来自我们自己的遗产。
this kind of collections clearly inspired by our own heritage.
嗯，你当然看到了阿拉的例子， 而且，嗯，
Um, of course you saw the example of Allah, and it's also, um,
伟大的工程例子 关节，还有，嗯，
great example of engineering the joints and also, um,
印着这种故事 在整个项目。
imprinting this kind of storytelling all over the project.
如你所见，在这个叶子，嗯，
So as you can see here in this leaf, um,
他从一个纯正的平面图案，呃，
he was shifted from a pure square pattern, uh,
一路嵌入不同的，嗯，
all the way to embedding different, um,
玛丽时尚史上典型的动机
motives that were typical from Mary fashion history.
所以她开始，嗯，
So she was starting, um,
平坦地读了方块 然后渐渐地伸展
just having a plain read of squares and then step by step iterating,
有些地方 比如说
uh, in some parts. For example,
在这里你已经可以看到这种花 或太阳，
here already you can see this kind of flowers or the sun,
这些都回溯到切尔克斯传统服饰。
and all of them go back to the traditional dress code of secretions.
最后一个图案列表 也有可能包含不同的材料
Um, last pattern list. Uh, it's also possible to include different materials.
所以我们，嗯，邀请你 探索不仅连接，
So we also, um, invite you to explore not only connections,
但是，嗯，举个例子，
but uh, um, for example,
你有一个可以连接到你的设计 或可能是
you have something to upcycle that can connect somehow to your design or can be
我们这里，嗯，
integrated. And here we have, um,
一个伟大的例子 从我们有它今年做的 由
a great example from the bootcamp we had it made this year that was made by
参与者，嗯，完全从零开始。
participants, um, completely from scratch.
我们循环这种睡衣帐篷
We upcycle this kind of bedwin tent. Uh,
实验室里有张大床单 所以实际上一切都是...
it was a large sheet available at the lab, so everything is actually, uh,
零浪费 基地是方形的 其余是金色的
zero waste. The base was square, um, and the rest is gold. That was, uh,
在墙上，呃，在实验室。
in the wall here, uh, at the lab. Um,
我马上回Ellation 当然
I'm going back one second to Ellation. And of course,
昨天，我们得知，这是一个过程 固定的形状在一起，
yesterday we had learned that was a process of fixing the shape together,
完全没有重叠的空隙
of tiling completely a plane without gaps of, um, overlapping.
呃，阿舍，呃，是这里的主人。
Uh, Asher, uh, was the master in this.
现在我们实际上可以做，呃，我们自己 在一瞬间的事情，呃，嗯，秒。
And now we are actually able to do, uh, ourselves in a matter, uh, of seconds.
因此，我们实际上能够解码，呃， 这种模式回到数学。
So we are actually able to decode, uh, this kind of patterns going back to math.
有一个不错的方法，呃，还有空间 在网格上，
And there's a nice way, uh, there also space on the grid,
角度上的空间，纯粹的数学上的空间，是适用于每一个，
space on angles, space on pure math. It's the same one that applied to every,
例如，阿拉伯图案，还有，嗯，
for example, Arabic patterns and also, um,
嗯，所有的戏剧性的 全世界。
uh, all the dramatical ones all over the world. Um,
这里有一个图表 也清晰地，比如，用颜色
here is a schematic also made a clear, for example, into colors
或我们能看到的东西，嗯， 一点点后。
or what we can actually see, uh, a little bit later.
Inkscape 或 Illustrator 都能创建
So either Inscape or Illustrator can actually create, uh,
像这样的配置 对于那些想探索，呃，零浪费，
configurations like this for the ones that want to explore, uh, zero waste,
嗯，嗯，图案，比如说，为了制造，
um, uh, pattern. For example, for the fabrication,
这显然很重要 基本上通过原则
this is something clearly important that basically through principles to take
第一，是否通过翻译实现异化？
into account. One, is it isation through translation? That means,
我们有一个起点，比如说，这里是一个广场
uh, we have a starting point. This can be, um, a square, for example.
上面发生的事情 我们把它带到底部
And what happens on top, uh, we take it to the bottom.
右边发生什么，我们把它左边。
What happens on the right, we take it to the left.
所以，如果我输出 除了广场 我拖它一路到底部，
So if I export apart from the square and I drag it all the way to the bottom,
我们做同样的事情，呃， 从左到右，
we do the same thing on, uh, from left to right,
基本上我有一个形状
and I basically have a shape
我可以克隆到不同的行 并创建一个模式。
that I can clone onto different rows and create a pattern.
我们稍后再谈
We're gonna have a little, uh, look later.
同样的事情，呃，例如在三角形的底部。
And the same thing happens, uh, for example, on the base of triangle.
因此，在这种情况下，我们可以旋转一个形状 应用这个，呃，呃，
So in this case, we can rotate a shape and applying this, uh, uh,
像三角形一样 所以60度
like a triangle. So 60 degrees,
我们可以有一个形状， 铺设和完全填满，
we can have a shape that teates and completely fills,
嗯，我们的飞机。
uh, our plane.
这个也是用 Illustrator 完成的，遵循相同的工作流。
This again, was done illustrator, and follows the same workflow.
有一个很好的，呃，在线发电机，
There is a nice, uh, online generator,
我敢打赌，还有许多其他 你可以找到，嗯，只是浏览在线。
and I bet there are many others that you can find, um, just browsing online.
呃，在这里你可以只是玩 一个特定的形状，
Uh, here you can just play with a given shape,
就像一个三角形的矩形 在Gon， 通过编辑角 在边缘，
like a triangle rectangle on gon, and by editing the corners on the edge,
你实际上能够自动，呃， 创建这种，呃，
you actually able automatically to, uh, create this kind of, uh,
因此，它也是，呃，
patterns into colors or three colors. So it's also, uh,
很高兴得到第一个，呃，
very good to get the first, uh,
进入镶嵌的世界。当然，
steps into the words of tessellation. Of course,
您可以探索自己的网格 并创建不同的创新
you can explore your own grid and also create different innovations for
有很多图案
many patterns. And
你真正应用到颜色的那一刻 就是你能看到，呃，
the moment you really apply to colors is the moment you can see, uh,
不仅是单一模块，还有大局
not only the single module, but the big picture.
这些是另一个例子，还有，嗯，放个链接。
These are another example. Also, um, put a link. Some refers to papers,
有些讲的是很好的教程，还有，
some refer to nice tutorials. There is also,
我们上次玩得很开心
um, a nice one in Inscape. We had a big last time,
所以这里不现场演示 Inkscape，我们稍后直接继续。
so I'm not gonna show Inscape, but we directly moved later.
我把链接留在这儿，你可以点击看看。
I leave you the link here, so you can just click and see. Um, it's, um,
需要10分钟的时间 才能创造出这样的东西
it takes, uh, for example, 10 minutes steps to create something like that.
这是通过 命令克隆。
This is through, uh, command cloning. So basically what happens,
你修改一个单一物体的方式， 时刻是，嗯，
and the way you modify one single object, the moment is, um,
和许多其他人有关
connected to many others.
所有你应用到单行的转换 都将被应用，呃，
All the transformation that you apply to one single line will be applied, uh,
相应.
accordingly.
我们正在转到直接的Themic笔记。
We're moving to the directly Themic note. Um,
我先从Fusion开始，只是...
I think I will start with fusion here. Just, uh, a couple of slides to drop.
我要做的，嗯，一个。
What I'm gonna do, um, in one.
故Fusion为三D.
So fusion is a three D.
参数建模器是控制参数的最好方法之一，也是
Parametric modeler is one of the best to control parameters and also
在设计中建立元素之间的关系
to establish relationships between the elements, uh, in a design.
嗯，这是第一次练习，我想。
Um, that's the first exercise, I think. Uh, also the first, uh,
感觉你可以创造这种模式。
feeling that you can have creating this kind of patterns.
通常我们先创建凸凹连接，再探索它们怎样
So usually we start creating a female and a male and explore the way they
互相连接
connect between each other. Um,
要么是软件Fusion 要么是其中之一 所以 抱歉
either software fusion or either, so, um, sorry,
Fusion 或 Rhino。
fusion or rhino. Uh,
让你有可能保存草图
give you the possibility to save the sketch. Uh,
作为矢量的设计。
the design as as a vector.
因此，作为一个PDF或DAF， 例如，对于排料，
So as a P D F or DAF for, for the nesting, for example,
以及 Illustrator 或 Inkscape。
and illustrator on scap.
记住的一件事是， 就像，呃，数字体。
And one thing to keep in mind is, again, like, uh, the digital body.
当然，我们说的是 RGB 色彩空间。
So of course we're talking about, uh, um, our g b space.
举例来说，我们将使用红色作为标准颜色来切割.
We're gonna use, for example, the red as a standard color to cut.
所以这一百五十五零是红色的密码
So the hundred 55 0 0 is the code for the red and
0.1，0.01毫米口径.
0.1, 0.01 millimeters.
这是要应用在全部切割零件上的描边。
It's gonna be the stroke that we applied to all the pieces that we want to cut.
嗯，如你所知， 这是所谓的排料，
Um, as you learn previously, this is called nesting,
这是一种吃东西和安排空间的方式。
and that's a way to kind of ate and organize the space.
所以我们尽量减少浪费， 但也减少机械时间。
So we minimize the waste as much as possible. But also the machining time.
我们昨天看到了一点，呃， 这是一个很好的开始方式，
We saw yesterday a little bit that, uh, it's a good way to start simple,
让凸件和凹件互相连接，
having a female and a male connecting, uh, each other,
但是，我们也可以永远地提炼它。
but also we can always iterate it.
因此，还有一种方法可以把它们结合起来，放在一个单一的模块中。
So there is also a way to combine that them together in a single module.
或者我还可以有其他添加剂的朋友形状来使用，呃，
Or I can also have other additive friend shapes to use, uh,
和它们结合
in combination with them. Mm.
再说一遍 如果你对Illustrator和矢量文件有点熟悉
This again, if you are a bit familiar with Illustrator and vector file, uh,
画得真好
well drawing yourself,
这是一个很好的方法 探索和模拟 不同类型，呃，
it's a good way to explore and simulate beforehand different kind of, uh,
我觉得也很有趣
patterns. I think it's also fun to see, um,
如何重叠
how they overlap
以及他们在数字世界能创造的东西。
and what they can create in digital world.
他们都跟随凹连接件加凸连接件的联系 设计会改变
They all follow a female plus male connection, and the design will change,
嗯，根据形状，
uh, according to the shape,
但你也可以增加三四个连接
but you can also add three or four, uh, connection.
当然，这很难想象
Of course, it's gonna be just a little bit harder to visualize this. Uh,
在两个D空间，
in a two D space,
我想我可以直接搬到，嗯，Fusion，
I think I can move directly to, um, fusion,
我希望你们还能看到我的屏幕
and I hope you can still see my screen. Um, I'm using a Mac,
所以，如果你使用一个Windows， 空间可能有点不同。
so if you're using a Windows, the space may be a little bit different.
呃，这基本上是接口。
Uh, this is basically the interface. So the moment you, uh, launch Fusion,
你会有，呃，呃， 这个在你眼前。
you're gonna have, uh, uh, this in front of your eyes.
你有一个仪表板 你总是可以，嗯，倒在左边。
You have a dashboard that you can always, um, collapse here on the left.
空文件是这样出现的，嗯，
And this is how appears the empty file, um,
Fusion工作，嗯， 像不同的，呃，参数化软件。
fusion works, um, like different, uh, parametric software.
基本上我们从哪里开始的 是一个草图。
Basically where we start from is creating a sketch.
草图是我们两架D飞机 首先
The sketch is our two D plane. So to begin with, we,
我们点击第一个周期， 这个周期被完全称为创建Sketch，
we click on the first cycle, which is called exactly Create Sketch,
我们选择立方体的顶部。当然，我总是可以旋转视图，
and we select the top of the cube. Of course, I can always rotate the view,
我只是点击输入，这就是我们所谓的草图模式。
and I just click to enter. This is what we call sketch mode. Uh,
第一个图标，好吧，我这样做，呃，嗯，再次，
the first icon, okay, I do it, uh, uh, again,
而当我真正做到这一点， 和一个图标在这里，按钮出现。
and the moment I actually do it, and one icon here, the button appears.
这是我的，嗯，草图记录在时间线上。
So this is my, um, sketch recorded in the timeline.
那么，嗯，如果我想回去的话，
So, um, if I want to go back,
基本上，我双击图标 并再次进入草图模式，
basically I double click on the icon and enter the sketch mode again,
进一步控制zi， 它是什么，
further control z i, it is what it,
我再次退出 草图模式
and I exit. Again, the sketch mode.
键盘上有很多快捷键 你可以使用，呃，与Fusion，
There are so many shortcuts on the keyboard that you can use, uh, with Fusion,
比如说，像Rhino等其他软件。
uh, like many other software like Rhino, for example. So, uh, suite, again,
我点击图标，我点击上面
we create a sketch. I click on the icon and I click here on the top. Now,
我用一套工具在上面，呃，会在我的眼前。
I use set of tools on top, uh, will be in front of my eyes. So for example,
我们想开始创造这个，嗯，两个圈子，
we want to start creating this, um, two circles,
用于激光切割的凸凹连接件。
a male and female interacting each other for laser cutting. So, um,
正如我在上面看到的，我已经看到，呃，工具，嗯，
as I can see here on top, I already see, uh, tools, um,
工具箱，我可以看到一个圆圈，我也可以在这里找到它们。
toolbox. I can see a circle and I can, I can also find them here.
我可以具体说明，如果我想，呃，
I can specify if I want them, uh,
从中心开始，或者从我通常开始，嗯，
to be starting from the center or from the point I usually start, um,
从中央，只是个人偏好，我可以说明
from the center. It's just, uh, a personal preference and I can specify it,
嗯，不管在这个网格上我想替换什么。
uh, whatever on this grid I wanted to replaced. So again,
我可以点击图标， 我点击任何地方我想，嗯，
I can click on the icon, I click anywhere I want to, um,
圆圈在我的网格， 我点击和释放。
the circle to be on my grid, and I click and I release.
嗯，如果船是蓝色的， 这意味着一个衣柜环，
Um, if the ship is blue, means is a closet loop,
我又来了，我点击圆圈
I do it again. I click on the circle,
我随意点击然后放出来
I click randomly and I release it. Uh,
正如我们之前所说，Fusion是一个很好的软件，嗯，
fusion, as we said earlier, is a nice software, um,
工作的各个方面，并联系《公约》各不同部分之间的关系
to work with dimensions and relate relationships between different parts of the
所以，呃，这将会是，呃，
design. So, uh, this is gonna be, uh,
你的一个好朋友，嗯，草图维度或d 在键盘。
a good friend of yours, uh, sketch dimension or d in the keyboard.
我们帮你给形状或设计定一个具体值。
We'll help you assign a specific value to a shape or to a design. So,
嗯，再说一遍，
um, again,
如果我点击D或Sketch维度并选择我形状的边缘，
if I click on D or Sketch Dimension and select the edge of my shape,
我实际上可以给它一个价值。
I'm actually able to give a value to this. So for example, let's say, um,
当然，我工作 在毫米。
of course I'm working in millimeters.
这是您可以在首选项中指定的东西 。
This is something you can specify in the preferences.
这么说吧，我想这个是60， 这是我的6厘米圆圈，嗯，
So let's say I want this to be 60, this is my six centimeter circle, uh,
像Rhino一样
created. And like Rhino,
我只能说，即使之后， 我希望这是五，
I can only say even afterwards that I want this to be instead five,
嗯，厘米，我可以，嗯，双击 值和改变
uh, centimeters, and I can just, uh, double click on the value and change
量度，改变尺寸。
the measure, change the dimension. Um,
有更好的方法做到这一点， 分配这种价值，
there is a better way to do this, to assign this kind of values,
所以，嗯，通常，
and it's gonna be here under modify. So, um, usually,
这也可以融入你的工作流程
and this is can be also integrated in your workflow, uh,
您可以修改并单击更改参数。
you go to modify and click on change parameters.
这是可以定义你价值的地方
And this is the place where you can define your, um, values. Um,
你可以给它一个名字， 你可以给它一个表达或只是一个数字。
you can give it a name, you can give it an expression or just a number.
例如，我想，嗯，如果我有很多多边形，
So for example, I want, uh, if I have many polygons,
我可以叫它边缘，我可以给它， 例如，60毫米。
I can call it edge and I can give it, for example, 60 millimeters.
我可以发表评论 也可以在这里创造
I can give it a comment or not, and okay, just to create it here.
每次我想改变任何价值
Every time I want to change any value,
我只是双击数字，我的尺寸会相应改变。
I just double click on the number and my dimension will change accordingly.
我又创造了一个 比如说，我叫长度
Um, I create another one. For example, I call length.
我可以用它做我的边缘，呃， 或者定义另一个具体的，呃，
I can use it for my edge, uh, or to define another specific, uh,
维度，我可以，例如，嗯，
dimension. And I can, for example, um,
20，所以两厘米，
20, so two centimeters,
我基本上领导他们来到这里。
and I basically lead them here. The moment I want to modify them, again,
我去，呃，前顶， 修改和改变参数， 我这里有它们。
I go to, uh, front top, modify and change parameters, and I have them here.
所以我现在可以改变这个 边缘和仍然，嗯，
So I can change now this to edge and still, um,
功能，它说这是50， 我也可以，例如，
the function, it says it's 50. I can also, for example,
说我要这个，嗯，边缘除以3。
say I want this to be, um, edge divided by three.
所以现在这当然是20了 比较一下，我和60了
So now of course this is gonna be 20. Contrast it, I'm fine with 60.
嗯，然后，呃，嗯，我说，
Um, then, uh,
菜单上有一个很好的工具
there's a nice tool here on top confusion in the menu,
这是限制和素描调色板 这就是...
which is the constraint and the sketch palette. This is where, um,
您可以在您的
you can actually assign relationship between different lines and shapes in your
画布，我们想创造这种关节
canvas. Um, let's say we want to create this kind of joints.
所以，基本上会有，嗯，简单的切口。
So there will be basically, um, simple cuts.
意思是，作为剪切， 我通常开始创作，嗯，
That means lines where as a cutting, I usually start creating, um,
访问，呃，实际上不会是 部分，呃，例如，嗯，
access that, uh, actually will not be part, uh, for example, um,
为此，我将点击线路。
of the design. To do so, I will be clicking on the line.
如果你和老鼠在一起， 你接近一些点，例如，
And if you are over with a mouse, you near some points, for example,
所以Fusion已经...
you can see sort of snaps. So fusion is already, um,
感觉这里有条直线
sensing somehow that here, there is a straight line.
这是我的极限
Here is the limitation of my edge,
我可以在曲线上指定一个点。
that I can specify a point here along the curve. So as you can see here,
我可以看到一条直线，我可以去创建我的通道。
I'm able to see a straight line. I can just go and create my access.
我点击，我点击第二点， 我在这里确认，嗯，
I click, I click the second point, and I confirm here with, um,
从键盘上逃出，我逃脱了选择。所以现在没有选择。
escape on the keyboard, I escape the selection. So now nothing is selected.
我可以决定我的轴线是不是一部分 或者我的设计
Uh, I can decide my axis to be part or not, or my design.
所以如果我把它留在现在， 我可以看到我有两个不同的衣柜循环。
So if I leave it as it is now, I can see I have two different closet loops.
所以如果我用激光切断它， 我最终会有一个圆形分裂成，
So if I laser cut this, I'm gonna end up having a circle split into,
嗯，为了避免这个，
uh, to avoid this,
我点击边缘或任何线 我不想成为我设计的一部分。
I click on the edge or any line I want not to be part of my design.
我在这里签了建筑型号
And I sign, uh, construction type here.
所以现在我的进入完全没有干扰任何形状。
So now my access is not interfering at all with any of the shape.
例如，我们可以说，嗯，
So for example, we can say, um,
让我们尝试建立这个，嗯，凹连接件连接。
let's try to create this, um, female connection.
现在我有一个轴作为参考点
So now I have an axis as a reference point,
我可以沿着圆圈的中间线走
and I can go on this, uh, middle line of the circle to place. For example,
我的第一个，呃，呃，连接。
my first, uh, uh, connection.
我希望这个完全在中间 这样我就可以使用任何我想要访问
I want this to be exactly in the middle so I can use any access I want to
指明方向，但也指明维度。
specify, uh, directions, but also dimensions. I, again,
我点击一个随机行 因为我更喜欢在以后签署数值。
I click a random line 'cause I prefer to sign the value later.
这意味着我可以去创造，并且再次，
That means that I can go to create and again,
草图维度。
sketch dimension. So I want the, this one for example, to be, uh,
比如说，通过，嗯，
can say linked for example, by, uh,
拆了两块，20块，现在完成了
split by two. So it was 20, now it's done.
我这样做只是为了告诉你一些命令。
And I'm doing this just to show you a couple of commands. So for example,
这里有个镜子
there is a mirror here,
你也可以在他们的需要下找到它。
and you can also find it under their needs. So
以类似的方式，现在，
in a similar way of right now,
Fusion是告诉你你想看到的物体是什么 是什么
fusion is telling you what are the objects that you want to mirror and which is
镜子线，所以我们当然需要 有东西在中间。
the mirror line. So of course we need to have something in between.
我又做了一次，我点击物体，我去看镜子
And I do it again. I click on the object. I went to mirror. Um,
这里的软件告诉我一个被选中，
here the software is telling me one is selected,
我点击镜像线，我还得到实时评论。
I click on the mirror line and I also get a review in real time.
所以现在我有镜像 我的线和Fusion 是添加这个
So now I have mirror my line and fusion is adding this
那种图标提醒我，我做到了。
kind of icons to remind me I did, I did this.
嗯，现在我已经定义了我的凹连接件， 让我们假设，我想，呃，
Uh, now that I have already defined my female, let's say I want, uh,
所有圆圈都充满了，呃， 凹连接件的连接和这些类型的线条。
all the circle be full of, uh, female connections and these kind of lines.
嗯，当然有很多方法可以做 你可以复制粘贴，
Uh, of course there are many ways to do it there. You can always copy paste it,
你可以复制它 你可以复制它
you can clone it. Um, you can it,
但你也可以创造一个模式 这样你就可以不用做双重工作了
but you can also create a pattern so you don't have to do double job. Um,
您可以在创建中创建命令。例如，这里可以找到命令，
you can create under create. Here you can find a command, for example,
圆圈，我创造的圆圈图案
it's a circle. So circular pattern I create,
我选择我要重复的台词
I select the line I want to repeat,
就像我需要选择某一点之前
and like before I need to select a certain point,
然后，我就可以，嗯，
the center of my circle. And then I'm able to, um,
正如我在预览中看到的， 来指定数量，
as I can see here in the preview, to specify the number of,
重复我的台词，创造平等空间
say repetition of my line and create equally spaced
比方说，你想，我们很高兴有四个
different cuts. For example, you want, we're happy with four,
我们希望他们，你知道， 甚至三个 使它有点不同。
we want them to be, you know, even three to make it a little bit different.
而现在，呃，当我们按， 好吧，我们有这种模式，
And now, uh, the moment we press, okay, we have this kind of pattern,
嗯，重复一遍，确定这是，嗯， 也记录下来。
uh, repeated to be sure this is, uh, also recorded. Here we have the icon.
所以，当我想改变这一点的时候，
So the moment I want to change this,
我不再有3个一，4个
and I'm not okay anymore by having three by one, four,
我可以来这里更新我的设计
I can just go here and update my design. Um,
当我点击，我点击完成我的草图。
the moment I click, I click finish my sketch. This is the,
如果我想再做一次改变，结果会怎样？
the result if I want to make any change again. Now this is kind of blocked,
所以我必须回到草图模式上 我可以看到上面
so I have to go back in the sketch mode and I can see here on top because
还有这个工具 再说一次 我可以...
there is this, uh, tool. And again, I can make, uh,
任何改变我的设计。
any change to my design. I want five,
我要3个，否则我改变主意，我要这个
I want three, or I change my mind. I want this to be
30. 因此，现在基本上一切都是相应的。
30. So everything now is basically accordingly.
所以他们当然不适合
So of course they won't fit.
我可以回到另一个维度
I can go back and specify in another dimension.
现在，我的联系，呃，呃， 空间在另一种方式，
And now my connection is, uh, uh, spaced in a different way of,
当然，我在这里只指定了参数。
of course I only, uh, specified the parameter here. I'm still able to move this,
嗯，沿着中间点 因为我没有，我没有说明，呃，
uh, along the middle point because I don't have, I didn't have specified, uh,
中间和我的线之间的距离
distance between the center and my line.
所以，如果我想百分百准确，
So if I want to be a hundred percent precise,
我已经很清楚我的最终形状 我的最终模式会如何
I already have clear idea on how my final shape, my final pattern is gonna be.
我还可以，呃，把最后一个限制。
I can also, uh, place the last constraint.
所以，现在我的设计是要去固定 而我实际上不能，呃，
So now my design is gonna be fixed and I cannot actually, uh,
通过拖拖拉拉的玩耍 我的形状在柜台上
play around by dragging and um, my shape all over the counter.
为了做到这一点，我确实创造了草图维度，
So to do that, I do create sketch dimension,
从中心到线的任何一个点，我可以表示，
and from the center to any of the point of my line, I can place,
嗯，我的价值。
um, my value.
所以我希望这是2010年 一切都会是
So I want this to be 2010 and everything will be
空间相应。
spaced accordingly. Or again,
我可以创建一个新的参数 并将此连接到另一个。
I can create a new parameter and I connect this somehow to the other.
我可以说边缘，乘以2，
I can say edge, multiply two,
这太大了
it's quite too big.
所以现在它也给了我 价值的名字是五，也许
So now it gives me also the name of the value is placed by five, maybe
3，我得到了多少，嗯，同样的一个。
three, and I kind of got more or less, um, the same one.
嗯，这里的菜单，
Uh, here on the menu,
您可以在文件夹中找到带有草图和你自己的草图。
you can find in the folder with sketches and your own sketch.
所以当一切都是，嗯， 你的草图被选中，隐藏，
So the moment everything is, um, your sketch is selected, hidden,
你也可以看到，嗯，你的设计 进入下面，呃，
you can also see the, um, your design coming in below, uh,
双击，你也可以...
double click. You can also, um,
再次输入空格或双击底部。
enter again the space or double click at the bottom.
当然，右键可以重命名为圆形
And of course right click, you can rename it the circle
或者直接另存为 DXF。
or you can just proceed to save as d xf.
譬如说，我们如何做第二个， 所以我们做了凹连接件，我们可以，嗯，
How do we make the second, for example, so we made the female, we can make, um,
凸连接件部分，还有许多方法
the male part. Uh, there are again, many ways to do it.
为了做到这一点。
To do it. Um,
我们可以从复制粘贴开始
we can start simple by copy pasting everything. So just, uh, selecting, um,
做，呃，对比C，控制V或右击移动，
doing, uh, contrast C, control V or right click move,
移动副本是一起的 所以两个对比 反V
move copy is together. So two contrast, C contra V.
我可以拿一份我的设计，这样我就可以用这个
And I can have a copy of my design. So I can use actually this,
嗯，作为一个模式，如果我们在开始时做一些非常简单的事情，
uh, as a pattern. If we're doing something very simple at the beginning,
这是非常建议这样做。
this is very suggested to do so. Uh,
最好让凸凹连接的相应间距保持一致，
the best practice will be keeping the same distance for the female of the male
所以，如果我们想有，
consistent. So if we want to just have,
嗯，不错，嗯，紧，嗯，
um, nice, uh, tight, um,
两个形状之间的稳定关节， 我们可以仅仅创造例如，
stable joint between two shapes, we can just create for example,
那个...
uh,
这里之间的线条，直到元圆或
the lines in between here until the meta circle or
甚至在形状之外一直保持线条
even continuing the line all the way outside of the shape.
接着使用类似 Rhino 中 Trim 的修剪命令。
And then introducing, for example, um, commands like streaming rhino.
当你选择图标时，
And the moment you select the icon,
您实际上可以删除行。
you are actually able to delete the lines.
你当然不想参与设计
You don't want to be part of the design, of course, uh,
设计的某些部分可能与前一个部分有关联.
some parts may of the design may be linked to the previous one.
所以，当你删除一些行， 你删除，呃，一些限制。
So the moment you delete some lines, you are deleting, uh, some constraints.
他们以前是联系在一起的，
They were previously linked,
说我们还在探索软件，没关系
say we're still, uh, exploring the software, that's fine. So, uh,
我其实不关心这个 我只是想让你...
I'm not actually caring of that. I just want you to, um,
告诉你，我可以做 我以前一样的事情。
to show you that I can do the same thing I did before.
所以，如果我不想这些线 成为我设计的一部分，
So if I don't want these lines to be part of my design,
我只是用梦想摆脱他们。
I just get rid of them with dream.
然后我创造了模式 复制，呃，
And then I create instead the pattern to replicate, uh,
关键部分。
the main part.
所以我回去创造一个安全模式。
So I go back to create a secure pattern.
我选了台词
I select the lines,
一个，嗯，中心点，
a certain, um, center point,
我已经能看到一个预览 如果我
and already I can see a preview of what's gonna happen if I
回答二，三或更多，呃，行。
answer two, three or more, uh, lines. So now
有办法有
there's a way of having
让凸凹连接结合。当然，这里还没有完全约束，
a female and a male part gather. Of course, again, this is not, uh,
所以，呃，当我移动，嗯，
linked. So, uh, the moment I move, um,
我需要另一个维度来修复这个强加。所以我再来一次。
I need another dimension to fix this imposition. So I do it again.
创建圆周阵列。
I create a secret pattern,
我创建的线 我想复制所有。
I create the lines I want to replicate all over.
而现在这个工具，例如，匹配，
And now this tool, for example, match,
举例来说，如果我出口这个，嗯，
I can get rid of the axis. So for example, if I'm exporting this, um,
任何地方都不会成为我计划的一部分
anywhere will not be part, will not consider as part of my design.
如果我对结果很满意 我可以把素描写完
And if I'm quite happy with the result, I can uh, just finish my sketch.
我也可以选择一切 我可以选择
I can also select everything. I can select,
如果我想排料的话， 还要移动， 把这个太靠近
also move and bring this too closer if I'm thinking of nesting everything
在Fusion，呃，如果我想这样做，
in fusion, uh, if I want to do that,
我也可以一起选择一切 而不是尖叫模式
I can also select everything together and instead of the squeal pattern,
创建长方形模式。所以我的所有设计都会自动复制，
create a rectangular pattern. So all my design will be automatically replicated,
嗯，在不同的画
uh, on different draw
根据我，呃，不同的参数。
according to my, uh, to different parameters.
因此，我还可以补充更多的内容。
So I can also add more.
这取决于我的需求，
It depends on my needs,
当然，和现在一样，我留下了一些重叠， 但是，呃，在这个软件，
of course, like before now, I left some overlapping, but uh, in this software,
一切都被记录下来，一切可以调整
everything is, uh, is recorded and everything can be adjusted. So I just go back
有的时候我有很多
on the icon of my pattern. Sometime I have too many,
我只要找到合适的一个 和某个地方。
I just have to find the right one with, with somewhere.
当然，这个国家确实做到了，呃，
Of course, the country did z uh,
撤销和重做也在这里。
undo and redo are also here on top.
它适用于许多软件。
And it was apply to to many software.
我没看见圣像，再做一次给你看
I don't see the icon. Just do it again to show you.
因此，从创建角图案， 我选择我想，呃，
So from create angular pattern, I select the ones I want to, uh,
给克隆人，我可以加5
to clone. I can put five,
我也可以选择方向
I can select also the direction
或插入一个值
and the space. Either, uh, inserting a value,
只是 呃 利用这个功能
just uh, using the snap function.
所以这是种，嗯， 让我们假设隔离 '因为它是一个浪费，
So this is kind of, um, let's say isolated 'cause it's a waste,
不完全是圆的
not really, it's a circle.
所以，你当然会 最终有这样的空间 在之间
So of course you are gonna end up having this kind of space in between the
形状，例如，可以决定重新使用或不用于设计。
shapes that you can decide to reuse it or not for your design, for example.
所以，一旦你最后 有类似的东西，呃，一些 少过，
So the moment you end up having something like this, uh, some less over,
你也可以想到，呃，为什么不再创造，
you can also think of, uh, why not creating again,
我不知道，这里有轴
I dunno, an axi here
然后再加入几个，然后你可以，呃，
and then a couple of joins. Then you can just, uh,
甚至复制粘贴或图案，然后通过图案复制
even copy paste or pattern all over and then replicate through a pattern
并适用于所有工作表。
and apply to, to all the sheet.
假设这次我们想用另一个软件 来更好地，嗯，
Let's say we want to use another software this time to better, um,
排料造型。
nest the shapes. So now I can call this, uh,
凸凹连接圆片。
female male circles
我就可以把它出口出去 这样我就能把他们保存成XF
and I can proceed to export it so I can save them as the XF
下一个顶部，好，圆圈就位
next top. Okay, circles in place
我转向Illustrator。
and I move to illustrator.
Illustrator 是 Adobe 的矢量软件。
Illustrator is a vector file is a, sorry, is a vector software from um, Adobe.
从文件、新文档创建新文件的那一刻，
The moment you create a new file from file, new document,
嗯，我总是说，
this is how the interface appears. Um, I always put,
尤其是因为在这里的实验室里
especially because in the lab here,
我们使用Illustrator 也与，例如，
we use illustrators also to communicate with the, so for example,
例如，我总是说，呃，
so for example, I always put, uh,
激光切割器床的尺寸，
the dimension of the bed of the laser cutter here,
我决定这个港口要600毫米左右
and I decide I want this port to be around one meter by 600 millimeters,
我要一个机场
which is exactly the dimension of the bed. Uh, I want one airport, uh,
横向画板，颜色模式使用 RGB。
orientation will be horizonal and the color mode will be, uh, R G b.
我不需要这个，我的皮肤是672 所以我可以留着这个，嗯，
I don't need this. My skin is 6 72, so I can keep this, uh,
作为下一个，嗯，
as a default for the next, um,
因此，这是如何，嗯，
explorations. So this is how, um,
界面在我创建新文档时就在这里，
the interface is here the moment I create a new document and
我总是把规则放在上面
I always begin enabling the rules here on top.
因此，有了Ctrl R常见的R，我可以创建这个，呃，
So with the Ctrl R common R I'm able to create this, uh,
让他们有磁性规则 我可以，呃，
enabling them magnetic rules that I can just, uh,
拖着我的账户，嗯，
drag and drop on my account to, um,
要不然就把事情搞砸 要不然就更清楚点
snap things to the grid or have a better understanding
嗯，嗯，可以放在我的床单上
on how things, uh, uh, can be placed. Um, on my sheet
我可以进口，例如， 或者你可以，呃，甚至打开，
I can import, for example, or you can just, uh, even open,
嗯，我的圆圈。
um, my circles.
好，不是这个
Okay? Okay, it's not this one
圆圈。
circles.
我可能已经有一个叫圆圈， 所以我可以再做一次。
I might have already one called circles, so I can do it again.
嗯，好吧，所以两个，
Um, okay, so two,
这是我的文件，选择用 Illustrator 打开，
this is my, I can just do open with illustrator and I always,
嗯，选择一对一的原尺寸和，呃，
um, choose one-to-one original size and, uh,
确定你的设计要用毫米
be sure your design wants to be to be in millimeters.
呃，这就是Fusion出口的方式。
Uh, so this is how from fusion got exported. One thing,
从三个D型号导出到
the moment you export from a three D model to,
要考虑的矢量文件也是，嗯，
to a vector file to consider is also, um,
如果有双线或不。
if there are double lines or not.
我用量子来创造这些线
I created this lines infusion by metering each of them
所以现在我当然不会单行
separately. So of course now I don't end up with a single line,
但是在管理员，呃，
but in administrator, uh,
我总是可以轻易摆脱 或加入线在一起。
I can always easily get rid or join lines together.
通过它，我选择了两行。
Through that, I select the two lines. For example,
我一个加入，我选择，嗯，
I one to join and I select, um,
从键盘命令J或控制J.
from the keyboard Command J or control J.
所以现在一切都是，呃，
So now everything is, uh,
我只能走这条线
this is only one line that I'm able to move around.
我对他们都一样 Sol
I do the same for all of them, Sol,
JLJ，这个可能是轴心国留下的
JL J. And uh, this might be left over from Axis,
所以，我其实不需要他们， 但如果我想继续，呃，
so I actually don't need them, but if I want to proceed, uh,
用激光切割这个，我可以，呃，嗯，列出它们。
with the laser cutting for this, I can just, uh, uh, list them.
比如，我可以把他们组成G组
For example, I can group them, group G
可以给它应用红色描边，
and I can apply, read a stroke for one, uh,
0.1毫米口径.
0.1 millimeters.
在这里双击描边颜色。
I double click on the stroke in my color here.
我敢肯定，这是，呃，网络颜色，RGB，
I be sure this is, uh, web colors, R G B,
我只是把红色，
and I just put red,
确认这里是 RGB 红色，255、0、0。
so I always be sure here is red 255, 0 0,
这是标准 如果我真的看不到我的设计
and this is the standard. If I'm not actually able to see my design,
为了便于查看，暂时也可以使用不同描边。
I can apply a different stroke for the moment.
现在它是一个团体。所以我实际上可以移动它们，嗯，周围。
And now it's a group. So I'm actually able to move them, um, around.
在 Illustrator 中很容易把形状排在一起。
And Illustrator is quite easy to nest shapes together. I,
我可以做，嗯，例如， 从键盘，
I can do, um, for example, from the keyboard,
这个基于矢量的软件有很多快捷键
there's many shortcuts to work with this, uh, vector based software. So, uh,
如果你按 例如，嗯，
if you press for example, um,
或选择Mac，你拖着丢掉一个形状，
alt or option for Mac and you drag and drop one shape,
你实际上能够创造，嗯， 他们的克隆。
you're actually able to create, um, a clone of them.
如果你继续按班子，你可以动了
And if you keep pressing shift, you can move
所以一轴是锁着的 所以我无法移动
on the same direction. So one axis is actually locked, so I'm not able to move,
嗯，上下，但我只能直走，你可以看到这里
uh, up and down, but I can only go straight. So you can see here
我选了小组，我以前选了
I'm selecting the group. I previously, uh, did and I select,
我点击我的键盘选择或选项，我选对夫妇
I click on my keyboard alt or option. I select the couple
我拉开它，还有从环境，snaps，呃，
and I space it. I have also from the settings, the snaps, uh,
启用 。
enabled.
因此，我也很容易找到什么是切合点或
So I can also find easily what are the tangent points or
当两分相遇，嗯，在我的设计，
when two points meet, um, in my design,
我再说一遍，还有...
I do it again. And there is, uh,
一旦我这样做，
once I do this,
我要是想完成 吃饱我肚子
if I want to have it done and ate kind of sating my full
端口，我也可以，呃， 从键盘 重复这个，呃，
port, I can also, uh, from the keyboard repeat this, uh,
命令，呃，按命令D，Orl D。
command, uh, pressing command D, orl D.
所以控制D允许我，嗯，
So control D is allowing me to, um,
所以当我用键盘按它时
to repeat the previous command. So the moment I press it in my keyboard,
而实际上有整排 在一秒钟，
and actually to have the full row in just one second,
现在我可以做同样的事情 所以我可以选择
and now I can just do the same thing. So I can select
我剪断了旧的排， 再说一次，我可以做，嗯，
I clip the old row, and again, I can do, um,
我一点击我键盘中的左键或选项， 我有这个，呃，
the moment I click alt or option in my keyboard, I have this, uh,
图标在这里，其他两个在一起。
icon here of the two others together. So I,
我按命令，呃，对不起， 我按所有的两种选择我，
I press command, uh, sorry, I press all two option I,
我按着转动，所以它不动。
I press shift together so it doesn't move. And again,
我继续做，呃，指挥d，
I keep doing, uh, command d,
CTRL D 让我完全添加选中的工作表。
CTRL D to have my completely add select sheet.
现在我们可以看到最后的例子了 嗯，它不适合我的激光剪床
Now we can see the last drop example. Um, it doesn't fit on my laser cut bed,
当然，我假设，呃，一个满板。
of course, I was assuming to have, uh, a full board.
大多数项目不会是这样的
This won't be the case for most of the projects.
我们可能最后会加入这样的东西。
So we probably end up adding something like this. Uh,
我回来
I go back,
我选择所有有共同控制A的东西 或者只是选择
I select everything with common A control A or just selecting
带着我的老鼠 再说一遍
with my mouse. And again,
把描边设为 0.1 mm。
I just apply a stroke to B 0.1 millimeters.
进去的时候，我确定我的台词在哪里
And at in, I make sure where my lines are here
确定你最终也会有一个封闭的循环。
to be sure that also you end up having a closed loop.
激光会形成一个圆形 你就能导出
So the laser is gonna actually create a circle and you'll be able to export
材料从董事会。
the material outta the board.
你可以把颜色和那一刻，嗯，
You can just reverse the color and the moment, um,
把描边和填充颜色交换后，可以
you, you feel the color is shaped from the stroke, you can actually,
请你确认一下 你有一个封闭的循环
uh, have the confirmation that you are being, uh, that you have a closed loop.
嗯，如果有关于这个问题， 我想你可以只是，呃，
Um, if there are questions about this, I think you can just, uh,
别冲动，大声说话 因为我看不见聊天
unmute yourself and speak up. 'cause I'm not able to see the chat. Uh,
否则我把它放在这里。
otherwise I leave it here.
我只是做我之前在幻灯片上承诺的事
And I just do what I was promising earlier in the slides. This there, um,
配方，所以我这里有另一个艺术板，我可以创造它，
that ation, so I have another art board here. I can just create it,
嗯，通过这个图标，它叫做艺术板， 或者只是，呃，
um, through this icon. It's called the art board, or just, uh,
创建一个新的文档。
create a new document. And again, adding a new, uh,
通过图标，我可以只是
sheet through the icon, I can just
放大或缩小 所以，让我们，
enlarge or make it smaller. So let's,
Illustrator 比较方便，也很有帮助。
illustrator is a, is a bit friendliness. It's, uh, quite helpful
我做了一个类似的方式 我在Fusion， 我创造了一个形状。
and I do in a similar way as I was doing in Fusion, I create a shape.
如你所见
So as you can see here,
您有不同设计工具的调色板。
you have a palette with different tools for to d design.
我可以看到如果我继续按， 我发现一个方形，一个唇，多边形，
I can see if I keep pressing, I find a square, a lips, polygon,
诸如此类 所以我想开始
et cetera, et cetera. So I want to start, uh,
所以，我点击矩形， 或者你可以看到，呃，
with a simple one. So I click on the rectangle, or as you can see here, uh,
m在键盘中。所以我点击它，我有两个选择。
m in the keyboard. So I click it and I have two options.
再说一遍，我可以选择第一点，并释放它。
Again, I can select the first point and release it.
所以，呃，现在我不知道我的尺寸。
So, uh, now I have no idea what my size is.
我可以去，比如说，
I can go, for example,
来塑造、改造、观察和控制它
to shape and transform and see and control it from here. So there are these,
这个，嗯，在这里说菜单 你可以，呃，
this, um, say menu here that you can, uh,
甚至把它拖到画布上
even drag and drop it closely to your canvas.
您也可以在此指定一个数字。 例如，30，
And you can also specify a number here. So for example, again, 30,
还有5060 如果这很重要的话
but also 50 60, if that matters,
或点亮正方形的瞬间，
or the moment you click up square,
你可以点击任何地方 从零开始分配，呃，维度。
you can click anywhere and assign from scratch, uh, dimension.
结果结果完全一样
So you end up having, uh, exactly the same result.
现在不使用描边，而是给形状填色。
I'm not working with the stroke, so I have it. My shape field,
这只是安装的一个例子。
this is just an example of the installation.
所以我用这个方块作为基地 有个不错的
So I'm using this square just as a base, and there is, uh, this nice,
嗯，非常友好的对齐工具 我听到上面。
uh, very friendly alignment tools that I hear on top.
所以我总是确定我的设计 在我的画布的中心。
So I always be sure my design is actually at the center of my, my canvas.
如果我点击我的形状，
And again, I can, uh, create an axis. If I click on my shape,
我看到这种捆绑，呃， 那种任何地方，特别是在中点。
I see this kind of bundles, uh, kind of everywhere, especially at the mid point.
所以我可以拖着，呃，
So I can just drag, uh,
中间的磁性规则 并创建坎瓦轴。
the magnetic rule here in the middle and create Canva axis.
然后，我们又在努力做我们在这张幻灯片上早些时候看到的。
And then again, we're trying to do what we saw earlier in this slide.
所以，如果上面发生什么事情，我们会发生在底部，反之亦然。
So if something happens on top, we're gonna happen at the bottom and vice versa.
所以从左到右或右到左
So from left to right or right to left, uh,
我有很多工具可以选在调色板上
I have many tools that I can choose from in the palette here. I can also, um,
使用这个被称为，呃，开拓者，
use this that are called, uh, Pathfinder,
类似的东西，你看到 在Rhino结合 不同的形状
something similar that you saw in the in rhino to combine different shapes
与众生同受崇拜，并加以减少，
together, but also to subtract them,
我真的可以做，嗯， 无论我想做什么 所以我可以，呃，
I can really do, um, whatever I want so I can, uh,
保持我的形状 从边缘，呃，
keep iterating my shape from the edge, uh,
和锅，例如，和关节。
with a pan, for example, and joint.
我的形状会由不同的点组成
So my shape would be composed of different points. Uh,
我们可以减去东西， 我们可以，嗯，使用锅， 我们可以使用，
we can subtract things, we can, um, use the pan, we can use the,
其它多边形。举例来说，我可以添加一个圆形。
another polygon. So example, I, I can add a circle.
假设我们可以，我们看到多边形准备好了，我们，
Uh, let's say we can, we saw the polygons ready, we,
我们可以试着用锅，把键盘或锅的图标放在这
we can try to use the pan. So pin the keyboard or the pan icon here,
你可以通过点击创建，嗯，
and you can create, um, by just clicking
不同点，我再来一次
different points. I do it again.
你可以随心所欲地放进去 这只是个测试
You can actually place them whatever you want. This is just, um, a test.
所以，然后创造，呃，类似的东西。
So then create, uh, something like this.
如果你看不到你所做的，你可以通过点击来改变颜色
If you don't see what you actually did, you can change the color by click
注意你的颜色，不要动，要蓝色
on your color. So stay, want this to be blue,
更简单 保持在线
actually make it more simple. Stay on the line.
我做了别的事 比如在另一边
I do something else. Uh, for example, on the other side.
所以当我也用笔点击的时候
So the moment I'll also click with the pen. I, uh,
如果我打开鼠标旁边的一点，
if I open with the mouse next to a point,
这将会被突出 一种锚。
this will be highlighted kind of a anchor.
这样我就能轻松地安顿一下我的，呃，
So I can also place easily just napping my, uh,
这里的笔。
pen here.
现在我有两个有点不同的循环
And now I have, uh, two slightly different loops.
例如，我可以选择我想要的两个
So for example, I can, uh, select the two I want to,
互相交流 互相交织 我选了两艘船
um, interact and intersect with. And I select the two ships that I made.
举例来说，我选择了任何一个寻找者。
And I, for example, choose any of the pathfinders.
我不知道是否清楚 我选了他们两个
So I didn't know if it was clear. Um, I select the two of them.
我想用一个变形器。所以，红色和蓝色。
I want to apply the a transformation on. So the, the, the red and the blue.
我点击这个图标，它叫做分裂。
I click on this icon, it's called divide.
所以，基本上我要有一个分裂。
So basically I'm gonna have a split.
这默认是一组的 所以我也可以使用，呃，
This by default comes in a group. So I can also use, uh,
右键单击并取消组合。基本上我已经完成了
right click and do ungroup. And basically I already have this done
如果我想再做一次，我也可以选择他们两个 并做好，
if I want to do it again, I can also select them both and do okay,
只要他们稍稍拦截一下
join them together. As long as they intercept a little bit,
子程序可以合并或分割它们。
the sub is able to merge them or split them. Um,
如果你有一个分裂， 所以像一条线或形状本身。
if you have a split into, so like a line or a shape itself.
所以，我把它拆开，我可以，嗯，放在这里 例如，
So I split it and I can, uh, put it here for example,
我可以这样，嗯，加入这两个
and I can do this way, um, join this two
自动的 你知道它加入是因为
automatically. Uh, you know that it's joined because, uh,
采用第二个形状的新颜色。
the new color of the second shape is adopted.
因此，重做这将是菜单的新形状。
So redo this will be a menu new shape.
所以它只是一个，再一次
So it is just one. And again,
到底发生了什么 在上，上，下，
what happens at the bottom up in the top, up at the bottom,
虽然我的形状不是完全的， 它不是非常惊人，我也可以，
while my shape is not totally, it's not very amazing, I can also,
比如说 操纵
um, for example, manipulate,
应用一种感觉或角度来修改。
applying kind of a feel it or angle to modify. Furthermore, the shape,
或者，如果我点击这里的第二个箭头， 我实际上可以，呃，
or if I click on the second arrow here, I'm actually able to, uh,
双击顶点，再次操纵，呃，
double click on the vertex and manipulate again, uh,
不同的方式，我的形状。
in a different way, my shape.
在这里，我可以做，嗯，
And here again, I can do, um,
嗯，一旦完成了，我很高兴，再次，
many things. Um, once this is done, I'm quite happy with that. Again,
我也可以做同样的事 或者只是做，嗯，
I can do the same or can just do, um,
复制粘贴，或者像我们以前一样， 我们拖下来，
copy paste it or like we did before, we drag it down,
复制一个复制品。所以复制它 选择或选择全部下来。
making a copy. So clone it with option or alt all the way down.
我也可以选择一切 并隐藏它。
I can also select everything and hide it.
所以我现在可以看见了，嗯，
So I'm actually able now to see, uh,
我复制，然后我可以再做一次。
that I copied and then I can do it again.
这个要删掉
This is gonna be subtracted
这将会是添加的。
and this is gonna be added. So
这将会是同一个形状的一部分，
this is gonna be part of the same shape and
我可以试着放下这个。
I can try to put this down.
右键，呃，让我们从后面走
So right click, uh, let's range it to the back.
所以我真的可以接受第二个
So I'm actually able to take the second,
给它一个颜色，只是为了区分他们俩。
give it a color just to distinguish the two of them. And we can say, I,
我想再减这个
I want to subtract this. Uh, again,
我可以摆脱轴线 现在我的形状已经定了
I can get rid of the axis and now my shape is kind of defined,
所以我可以把它复制出来 看看这有多完美
so I can just clone it and see how perfectly this
是，呃， 隔离我的空间。
is. Uh, desolating my space.
再说一遍，我选择一切
Again, I select everything
我可以空闲，也可以拖走它们
I can space or I can just drag and drop them.
当然，你真的可以 准确的一针。
Of course, you can really be precise with a snap.
随你何时
The moment you have to.
你们也可以确定
You can also be sure
这不太精确，你也可以点击某个点。
this is not very precise. You can also click, um, on a certain point.
所以，你实际上可以 打破像素。
So you're actually able to snap the pixel.
确认只使用描边，而不使用填充。
We want to be sure you apply just the stroke and not the feeling.
┮┮Τ狥「常睲贰и稱 type
So everything is cleaner. And I want to type your listing.
这基本上是有时 当你有关闭循环和模式，
That is basically sometimes when you have closed loop and patterns,
嗯，就像在这种情况下， 你真的想优化 机器时间。
uh, like in this case, you really want to optimize also the machine time.
而且，呃，有时你会有，
And, uh, sometimes you are gonna have,
特别是如果你像这样排料 双线
especially if you nest the pieces like this, uh, a double line. So you have
这个边缘会被复制到上面 所以大多数情况下
this edge is gonna be replicated on top of this one. So in most of the cases,
帮助知道，嗯，一个叫做切 在你的，
useful to know, um, a command called cut in your,
你可以通过它，嗯，通过点击这里，剪刀。
you can access through it, um, by clicking here, the scissors.
所以如果你点击两个不同的点
So if you just click on two different points,
你实际上能够打破循环 摆脱双线。
you're actually able to break the loop and get rid of the double line.
所以，现在你的搭档，呃， 让我们说更正确。
So now your partner will be, uh, let's say more correct.
再说一遍 你可以...
And again, you can just, uh,
带着像素，在回去的路上移动它。
take the pixel and move it on the way back as it was before. So again,
这，呃，将是共同的。
this, uh, is gonna be in common.
所以我也可以读到这个。
So I can also get read of this one.
现在，我保留，我可以 克隆我的按钮了。
And now I kept, I can keep cloning my button all over.
我可以重复同样的话
I can repeat the same
甚至改造和加入，嗯， 在一起只有一行，
and even transform and join, um, together in only one line,
所有底线和所有，嗯，顶线一起。
all the bottom lines and all the, um, top lines together.
然后，我也可以这样做，当然，我也可以这样做 在结尾。我删除，
And then I can do the same, of course, I can also do it at the end. I delete,
所有的人 我创造了一条新线 一条新的连续线
uh, all of them. I create a new line, uh, a new continuous line.
所以很多设计师，呃， 更干净，同样，嗯，
So many designers will be, uh, much more clean also in terms of, uh,
编造，然后，
fabrication. Then again,
我可以应用描边。
I can apply a stroke. Can,
我认为从这里选 或者双击柱。
I think pick it from here or double click on the column.
因此，它会再次是红色， 255，0，0。
So it is gonna be red again, 2 55, 0, 0.
当然
Of course,
我甚至可以把这里的东西都拼凑起来
I can group everything even here now with the a integrated
或者我也可以操纵它
ai. Or I can also, uh, manipulate it.
所以我绝对可以 放大或下
So I can definitely scale it up or down the
颜色，我也可以做一些事情
color. I can also do, um, a couple of things
或只是，嗯，说，我很高兴 设计，为了最后敲定它，
more or just, uh, say I'm happy with the design and in order to finalize it,
我可以把这个放回去0.1毫米
I can just apply this back to be 0.1 millimeters
比如说，呃，当然，保存它和出口，
and, uh, of course save it and export, for example,
作为 PD F 或任何其他矢量文件
as a P D F or any other vector file for
如果你的 Illustrator 可以直接连接激光设备，
in case illustrator in your case is connected directly to the laser.
你可以去打印 并发送到，嗯，画，
You can just go to print and send it to, um, draw,
工作控制或任何软件
uh, job control or any of the software there. So
再说一次，我可以做出口
again, I can just do export as
连SV G圈，两个导出
even S V G circles. Two export.
你可以把缺省留在这儿，当然，它说Vg。
You can keep the default here. Of course, it says vg.
所以现在你知道 有一个代码，呃，
So now you know that there is actually a code and, uh,
在文档中按“好”键。您可以将其链接为“a，
press okay in your documentation. You can link it as a,
作为文件再次作为PDF，或者Daf。
as a file as a P D F again, or daf. You can just, uh,
放在文件文件夹里 放在文档里
put it in the files folder, uh, inside the documentation.
所以你的文件会放在这
So your file is gonna be placed here.
其实我选择了一切
I actually selected, um, everything.
所以两块板子都在我的大设计里
So both of the boards will be in our part of my big design.
嗯，我们可以快速移动，呃，到Rhino 只是，嗯，
Um, we can quickly move, uh, onto Rhino just to, um,
很快看到Fusion的区别
quickly see the difference between Fusion. Uh, again,
这是Rhino在Mac上的版本 所以可能有点...
this is Rhino version on the Mac, so it might be a little bit, uh,
可能和Windows不同
even more than little bit maybe different from Windows.
当然，命令是一样的。
But of course the commands are the same.
上面有菜单，还有边菜单
There is a top menu and there is a side one. Uh, we're gonna use,
嗯，大部分只是你在这里看到的评论。
um, mostly just the comments that you see here. And I think to begin with,
嗯，你可以看到，呃，
it's good to light that. Uh, as you can see here, uh,
左边是一个很好的做法 拥有这些，嗯，
on the left is a good practice to have most of these, um,
所以，呃，当你看到之前，
snap enabled. So, uh, when you saw before,
当我走近一条线或，嗯， 某些形状的我的老鼠，
when I go nearby a line or, um, certain shape of my mouse,
и痷稱垛
I really want to, um,
确定我点击特定像素的某个特定点。
to be sure I click onto a specific pixel on a specific point.
所以我会保持，嗯，终点，中点，
So I'm gonna keep, um, the end point, the midpoint,
中间的交叉点，
the center intersection,
作为我设计的默认
and as a default in my design. Uh,
我们可以尝试做一些类似的事情 我们做了，呃，Fusion。
and we can try to do something similar that we did, uh, with Fusion.
所以，现在我们要看到 参数模型与，呃，
So now we're gonna see the difference of between a parametric modeler and, uh,
Rhino这样的软件能处理几何问题
a software like Rhino that handles geometries. Uh, but not only, uh,
例如，我们可以用方形矩形做一个例子。
we can do an example with squares rectangle, for example. So,
这是我们正在研究的界面 这是我的视角
uh, this is the interface we'll be working on, and this is my view.
我不需要点击像Fusion，呃，
I don't have to click like fusion, uh,
从头开始，在我的顶部，呃，或左边，
already from the beginning on my top front, uh, or left,
嗯，通过这个图标，我可以完全看到。
uh, through this icon I can see altogether.
所以这里会发生什么 发生在前面和右边
So what happens here is gonna happen, uh, in the front and in the right,
当然，也从各自的观点和角度出发。
of course, at the respective views and also in the perspective.
我可以点击其中任何一个 放大，放大模式 看它们是否，嗯，
I can click on any of them to zoom, zoom mode to see if they're, um,
连线，我可以点击顶部
connected. And I can just, uh, click on the top.
因为我基本上要研究这个 所以这是...
'cause I'm gonna work basically into this. So this is the, um,
永远确定你的工作 从上方。
always be sure you're working from the top side.
嗯，再次， 我们可以创建长方形 类似的方式Fusion。
Uh, again, we can create a rectangular in a similar way of fusion.
所以点击这里的图标， 我可以，呃，嗯，
So clicking on the icon here, and I can just, uh, uh,
Rhino告诉我，从哪里开始，坐标是什么？
rhino is telling me, uh, where to begin. So what are the coordinates? Where,
我的第一点会放在画布上吗？
where is my first point gonna be on the canvas? Um,
我被训练成产品设计师
I'm trained as a product designer,
所以，当然我的飞机也会，呃，例如，嗯，
so of course my plane also is gonna be, uh, for example, um,
所以，我通常从中间开始，嗯，
coordinate. So I usually begin at the center, um,
所以，我只是输入0，嗯，
of my grid that is actually given here. So I just input zero, um,
跟我的出身一样是零
common zero as my origin. Uh,
我创建，嗯，基本上可以， 我可以指定长度，
and I create, um, basically can, I can specify the length,
边缘，角落，所以我也可以说，这个，
the edge, the corner. So I can also say, again, this,
有60比60作为方块，
have it 60 by 60 as a square,
我可以确定这其实是60，呃， 通过看上面。
and I can be sure this actually 60, uh, by looking on top.
我可以继续维度。
And I can go on dimension.
我可以看到有一个命令叫做衬线维度。
I can see there is a command called liner dimension.
从这里我可以看到，这其实是60。
And I can see from here to here, this is actually 60.
这有点误导人 不像Fusion
Um, it is a bit misleading. It is not like fusion,
所以这样不行
so it doesn't work, uh, like that.
我不能双击并相应更改数值，我也可以，呃，
I cannot double click and change the value accordingly. I can also just, uh,
校验我的尺寸是六厘米
debug and verify that my dimension is actually six centimeters.
当然 如果你的线不是毫米
Of course. Uh, please, if your line is not a millimeters,
回到那个...
go back to uh,
5，并探索解剖， 确定这是在两毫米多。
five and explore the dissecting and be sure this is at two millimeters more.
因为我们在处理，呃，小物体， 但也，嗯，
'cause we're dealing with, uh, small objects, but also, um,
0.1，0.2毫米，尤其是这个星期.
0.1, 0.2 millimeters, especially for this week.
嗯，所以再次，这个， 我，我发现它在，呃，维度，
Um, so again, this, I, I found it on the, uh, dimension,
Leonard的维度，我只是点击，嗯，
Leonard dimension, and I just click, um,
几点来说明我的距离。
couple of points to specify my distance.
嗯，有很多方法， 当然还有RiNo来创造，比如，嗯，
Um, there are many ways, of course also RiNo to create something like, uh,
这些模式，我们可以开始，嗯，
these patterns. We can start, um,
例如创建访问。
creating an access, for example. And again,
我们可以看到，根据我们选择的坐标，
we can see here that according to the snaps that we selected,
所以如果我靠近边缘
we can have sort of guidelines. So if I go closer to the edge,
我可以强调中间的摩。
I can highlight the mid mo.
所以我可以在这里点击 并在这里创建一条线。
So I can just click here and create a line all the way here.
我可以通过键盘确认 逃脱或箭头。
I can confirm through the keyboard and escape or the arrow.
为了逃避任何选择
So to escape any selection,
我也可以选择忽略轴线 然后继续
I can also choose, for example, to ignore the axis and just proceed, uh,
创建一条线像我们以前一样。
creating a line like we did before.
再说一遍，我要用质量线，我可以创造
So again, I'm gonna use the quality line. I can create
先放一点，再放第二句
placing one point first, and then the second a line,
如果我已经知道它的价值， 它是，它会是 更容易让我知道。
if I already know the value, it's, it's gonna be easier for me to know.
因此，我们可以再次设定两个20。
So again, we can set two 20.
所以我可以把第一点放在某个地方 说
So I can place the first point somewhere and just say,
我希望这是20。
I want this to be 20.
好吗？
Okay?
如果我想在后面 只是确保它是20，再次，
If I want to the back just to make sure it's 20, again,
我访问两个维度并点击线性维度并选择两个点
I access two dimension and click on linear dimension and select two points
其实是20岁
and is actually 20,
我并不需要这个，我可以删除它。
I don't really need this and I can just delete it. Uh,
团结是组织起来的好方法
united is a nice way to, um, organize.
所以我可以移动它 或通过这里的 gi，形状，
So I can just move this around or through the gimbal here, the shapes,
嗯，为了正确放置这个， 让我们至少说，呃，
uh, to place this correctly, let's say at least, uh,
在我的中轴线，我也可以
at the middle here of my axis, I can also
选择行。我想移动
select line. I want to move
在命令行右侧，移动更多的曲线。
right in the command line, move more curve.
既然我把这东西放下了 我现在不需要中心了
And since I have this alighted, I don't need the center now,
能够保持点中点。
can keep the point midpoint.
我只想看看中间点的确切位置 这样我就可以从点到点
I just need to see exactly where the midpoint is so I can move from point to
从点到边 从中间
point, from point to edge, from the middle of this
任何地点，任何我想要的地方。
to any place, any location I want this to be. So for example, here
再说一遍，我不需要这些台词，所以我可以把它扔掉。
again, I don't really need these lines, so I can just get rid of it.
再说一次，我可以创造出类似的方式 就像我们Fusion一样，呃，一种模式，
And again, I can create a similar way like we did fusion, uh, a pattern,
循环图案 如你所见 软件真的不重要
a circular pattern. So as you can see, uh, the software really doesn't matter.
工作流程基本一样
The workflow is mostly the same. Uh,
你可以选择行 并写，嗯，阵列在，嗯，
you can select the line and write, um, array in, um,
每一个软件 作为一个不同的，嗯，嗯，
every software as a different, um, um,
一套可以选择的规则和命令。
set of rules and commands that you can choose from. Um,
你可以开始打字的东西，嗯，
you can start typing something and, uh,
您也可以访问这里所有不同的命令。
you can also already accessing all the different, uh, commands here. Uh,
我将使用 ArrayPolar，即极轴阵列。
I'm gonna use the one called the ray polar. So, um, right now,
再说一次，它告诉我，嗯， 具体我要做什么。
again, it's telling me, um, to specify what I want to do. So,
嗯，我也可以从命令开始 然后，呃，
uh, I can also begin with the command and then, uh,
之后只是选择线条 这样我就可以再写一遍 阵列颜色
afterwards just selecting the line so I can write again, array color,
选择对象到数组。 我按下输入 。
select objects to array. I press enter when down.
所以大多数命令都会这样
So most of the commands will work this way. And,
中心，我很幸运能有它
uh, the center, I'm lucky enough to have it here. So I,
我删除了访问权限，所以我需要它。
well, I deleted the access, so I actually needed it. I go back in time.
幸运的是，呃，这是允许的。
Fortunately, uh, that's allowed.
我回去先点击我的台词 或者再输入命令
I go back to click my line first or just input the command again.
在 Rhino 中，按键盘上的——
Um, rhino, if you press, um, backspace,
嗯，空间栏 在你的键盘，
um, the space bars are in your keyboard,
你可以重复上一个命令，这样比较容易
you can actually repeat the previous command. So it's just easier, um,
因此，
to work with keyboards sometimes in this kind of software. So again,
选择对象到阵列将是我的线条。
select objects to array is gonna be my line.
把一个小点 指定中心
And turn one down and specify the center.
和Fusion类似
So this is gonna be in the center. And uh, again, similar to fusion,
之前我们加了三个
how many items we want to put. Previously we added three.
现在我们要四点，等我完事
Now we're gonna go for four. So when I'm done,
我曾经确认，我可以说明角度。
I used to confirm and I can specify the angle.
因此，它会是所有的圆。
So it's gonna be all over circle.
所以设为 360°。
So three under 60 degree, I press it here
这是我的预览，我很高兴
and here is my, uh, preview. So I'm happy with that. Yes,
我点击，我，
I clicked on, I,
我能读到其他不需要的台词
I can just get read the, um, the other lines that I don't need.
当然，再次， 创造凸连接件的部分或组合，
Of course, again, to create the male part or a combination,
说到凹连接件和凸连接件
let's say of female and male part, uh,
你可以做chondro CDL V 复制同样的一个。
you can do chondro CDL V and clone the same one.
嗯，有很多方法可以做到这一点。
Um, there are many ways to do it. For example,
我们想有其他的连接在这里， 类似于嗯，
we want to have the other connections here, similar to um,
此形状和垂直部分。
this shape and the vertical part.
因此，艾诺可以做这样的事情。我可以选择两行。
So Aino can actually do something like this. I can just select the two lines.
我可以，嗯，继续线 这样我就可以，呃，
I can, um, continue the line so I can, uh,
嗯，选择这种图标。
um, select this kind of icon.
如果你已经知道了 我可以决定把一个因素 向大方向扩展
I can decide to scale a factor in wide direction if you already know.
或者，我可以只是，呃，呃，
Or I can just, uh, uh,
让他们到处走 以防我需要修剪线路
let them go all over the shape in case I need to trim the line
与其他线路交叉
intersecting with other lines
并试图做这样的事情。
and trying to do something like this. I can actually do, um,
复制粘贴，我以后可以创造一个图案来获得我的，我的，我的形状.
copy paste. I can create a pattern later to get my, my, my shape.
有很多办法，我也可以...
There are many ways to do it. I can also, uh,
在此创建一条线作为参考，然后将一些线改为
create a line here as a reference and then some instead of
比如说，复制粘贴，我可以做类似，呃，
copy pasting, for example, I can do similar like, uh,
与设置的护理相反 我可以决定，
opposite of set care and I can decide,
额...
um,
从这里到这里的距离或指点
the distance or point to point from this one to the,
到另一个点，比如说。
to the other point, like this for example.
也就是说我以某种价值移动了
So I just opposite one line. That means I moved, uh, at a certain value,
我的台词有参考文献， 现在我可以决定，嗯，
my line to have reference, and now I can just decide to, um,
不管有没有，我也可以加入
to have it part of my design or not. I can also add it if I want.
通过这个图标，实际上能够， 把它放回去，
And through this icon actually able to, to put it back,
我做我以前做过的事
I do what I was doing before.
我也可以通过这个计划来移动一下
I can also move it a little bit through this scheme,
但我选了他们两个 我希望他们...
but I select them both. I want them to be, uh,
现在不是设计的一部分，它们会造成一些混乱
not part now of my design. They can create some confusion.
我选择这样继续排行
I choose to continue the lines this way.
现在我想知道我的台词在哪里。
And now I want to know where actually my lines were.
举个例子 我想修剪它
Okay, so for example, uh, I want to, I want to trim it.
基本上我有过
Basically I had
像这样，我想...
Something like this here. Now, um, I'm trying to make,
正如你们在物体里看到的 其他部分我可以...
as you can see here in the object, uh, the other parts I can just, uh,
与凹连接件部分相交 所以这将是一个模块，呃，
intersect with the female part. So it's gonna be a module, uh,
它同时有凹槽这样的凹连接，以及凸连接。
that has together female parts like these cats and male at the same time.
所以，呃，在一种或另一种 不同的方式与Fusion，
So, uh, in an or and in a different way from fusion,
从呃，呃，一个更好的 数学方式在一个多，
from uh, uh, a better way of math in a more,
假设我还在集思广益
let's say I'm still brainstorming my shape. I just, uh,
探索不同的指令，这是允许的
exploring different commands. So that's so kind of allowed.
呃，我可以再次使用修剪 如果我不知道在哪里的图标，
Uh, I can use trim again if I don't know where's the icon,
它会在这里，
it's gonna be here,
但我有时可以更舒服 修剪，现在我有线
but I can just more comfortable sometimes with the trim now that I have lines
互相交织，我可以...
intersect with it's intersecting between each other. I can just, uh,
我想修剪哪条线
side which kind of lines I want to trim. Um,
我想脱身
I want to remove
基本上，这里的线 在中间，只是离开这个部分。
basically the lines here in between and just leave this part. So again,
我可以选择，嗯，
I can select, um,
再次命令，软件告诉我 选择剪切对象。
the command again and the software is telling me select the cutting object.
所以，嗯，我想创造这样的东西。
So, um, I want to create something like this.
两条线横向会是我的切口对象.
The two lines horizontal will be my cutting object.
按下输入一个并选择您想要梦想的对象 。
Press enter one down and select the objects you want to dream.
所以我想在这里做梦
So I want to dream the ones here.
再说一次，我做同样的事情 或者可以只是，呃，
And again, I do the same thing or can just, uh,
缩短我不需要的其他人
shorten the others that I really don't need. So again,
空间条剪，我也可以做同样的事情。
space bar trim and I can do the same.
选择剪切对象，这个输入
So select the cutting object. This one enter,
再说一次，我可以决定
and again, I can decide
以缩短去掉一条我不需要的线。
to make it shorter to remove a line that I don't need.
基本上这就是我的计划。
And basically this is what I plan to do.
因此这个方形同时包含凸件与凹连接。
So I have a square that is together, male part, female part and male part.
当然，我也可以，如果我想隔离 在Rhino，呃，
And of course I can also, if I want isolate in rhino, uh,
因为某种原因，当我试图复制粘贴，呃，
for some reason the moment I try to copy paste, uh,
我的复制命令不会因为这种版本而禁用。
my copy command is not disabled for this kind of version. So, um,
这里尝试用 Offset，
I always try to play around and do offset
选择要偏移的曲线。
and I can also, uh, select on the curve I want to offset.
是啊，它的工作原理相同， 但通常我只是更舒适 在，嗯，
Yeah, it works the same, but usually I'm just more comfortable in, um,
这就是我建议做的，嗯，这种，嗯，
and that's what I recommend to do, um, this kind of, um,
任何软件上都没有嵌入丝
nesting sation in none of the software either scape or
Illustrator。因此我可以继续，
illustrator. So I can just go, uh,
并告诉布莱恩 当我完成我的设计工具出口，
and tell Brian when I'm done with my design tool export,
也许最后一件事 我们可以在这里做 在软件，
the maybe last thing that we can do here in the software,
您可以选择所有的东西， 确定在此层中
you can select everything and be sure also here in this layers
面板为嗯，
panel to um,
调整线条或激光切割。
adjust the line or laser cutting. So we're ready in, uh,
RGB 色彩空间，也可以通过点击图层确认。
R G B space, we can make sure also clicking on the layer.
我们这里有线型 所以我们得确定这是连续的
Uh, here we have, uh, line type. So we have to be sure this is continuous.
我们有一个默认值，这是我们要删除的电话
We have a default. This is the call we want to set to red.
这里可以设置 RGB，
So let's be sure here we can put R R G B 20,
红色为 255。
um, 55 red.
如果这能帮助你视线，你就可以，嗯，
And also if this helps you to visualize the thread, you can actually, um,
选中此项并更改层本身的外观。
select this and change the appearance of the layer itself.
所以现在它会是100%的 外表和呃，
So now it's gonna be hundred percent the appearance and uh,
红色的属性，当然，嗯，
um, the attribute of the color red, of course, um,
说到做到，说到做到
you can scale, you can decide a point
或百分比或距离。
or percentage or a distance. So example here,
你还想玩 嗯，规模。
you want also to play with um, scale.
我认为Rhino是一个非常好的软件来做到这一点。
I think Rhino is a very good software to do that.
或者可以缩放重复命令。例如，
Or you can scale repeating the command. For example,
从这一点，您可以输入一个像8厘米的数字。
from this point, you can input a number like eight centimeter.
现在它会更大
Now it's gonna be bigger
你可以旋转它，
or et et cetera. You can rotate it,
可以结合其他多边形，其他形状。你可以创建，
you can combine other polygons, other shapes. You can create,
嗯，其他凹连接件连接。
um, other female connections.
因此，越像切 你拥有的几何， 例如，越多，
So the more like cuts you have inside of geometry, for example, the more,
嗯，有空间玩和交叉 不同的模块，你有。
uh, room to play and intersect different modules you have.
嗯，我猜就是这样，所以，
Um, and that's it I guess. So again,
最后一件事，就去存档。
last thing and just go to file. Of course,
我也建议你自动节省开支
I also recommend you to enable the automatic savings.
所以偶尔我知道我们会为你做这个工作
So every once in a while I know we'll do this job for you.
你不必担心失去任何文件 我们就可以...
You don't have to be worried of losing any file and we can just, uh,
当然，如果想要，则导出选中。
export selected if just you want that. Of course. Um,
我有两个不同的许可证，现在用的不是正确的那个，
I have two different license. Um, I'm not using the correct one,
因此不能导出，但后续工作流基本上
so I am not able to export it, but uh, the workflow is gonna be basically, uh,
测试其他软件。
testing of the other software.
我想我可以停止，嗯，屏幕共享
I think I can stop, um, screen sharing
和嗯，检查 聊天或呃，只是想，嗯，
and um, check the chat or uh, just want to um,
如果你有问题的话，请说清楚
speak up in case you have questions. I hoped it was quite clear,
我不知道，如果你试图 同时对我做，或，嗯，
I dunno if you were trying at the same time to do it with me or, um,
我还有其他疑问
I raised any other doubts
我面前还有一些例子。
I also have here in front of me, for example, some of the examples.
这就是我们讨论的幻灯片上的那个。
So that was the one in the slide we talked about.
它是一个大床单，被回收在一个模块
It was a big sheet that was recycled in a modular
组装是，嗯，
assembly that was, um,
一个由不同方块组成的袋子。所以基本上这就是我们所做的。
a bag made of different squares together. So basically this is what we did.
现在，在软件 真正需要，呃，
Now in the, in the software that actually takes, uh,
当你开始练习 大约10分钟，
the moment you start practicing around 10 minutes,
20分钟后再处理这些测地仪
20 minutes to deal with these geometers, again,
所以当你有一条线的时候
you can see them as a pattern. So the moment you have one line,
您可以在边沿的图案上排列相同的线条。
you can array on pattern the same line all over the edges.
圆圈也一样
The same happen for, um, the circle.
因此，这是一个凹连接件的部分连接
So that was a female part connecting to
凸连接件部分，也许背面比较清楚
a male part. Maybe it's more clear from the back.
你可以看到这种箭头连接在内部。
You can see this sort of arrows connecting inside.
测试形状后，如果能做这样的
If you are able, after you test your shape to do this kind of test, like, uh,
拉扯和受力测试，就说明
cool and stress, that means that uh, your joint is actually quite stable.
它可以向前移动，嗯，是削减。
It can just move forward, um, to is cutting.
所以如果可以的话
So if that's okay,
当然，当你有4个 在你有8，
of course the moment you have four at the moment you have eight,
那会更稳定
that's gonna be way much more stable.
这对圈子来说是类似的
That's a similar, um, for the circles.
我也有我们以前通过木头看到的例子
And I also have an example of what we saw before through the kigami,
举个例子
for example.
所以有一个部分是凹连接件 包含在内
So there is one part which is a female that includes inside
里面包含凸件，所以不需要额外片材或另一套模块。
a male part. So I don't need an extra sheet, an extra pattern.
我可以翻转我的连接 插入
I can just flip my connection and inserted
换成另一个形状，没有这个形状 基本上是一样的。
onto another shape, which is basically the same without this one.
所以我用里面的连接，对不起，我的背景。
So I use the connection inside, sorry, my background.
摆
Okay.
所以我可以把两者结合起来
So I can just combine this two together
我最后有这种，呃，
and uh, I end up having this kind of, uh,
空的空间，负的空间，实际上可以，呃，帮助
empty space, negative space that can actually be, uh, helpful
来创造一些东西
to create something
或同但别.
or same but different.
这是一个小部分，也可以以另一种方式孤立，
That's a little part that can be also isolated in another way,
但还是和这个完全一样
but still as the same exactly connection of this one.
所以我也可以说 我想使用，呃，额外的材料，
So I can also say I want to use, uh, an extra material,
一个额外的模式 不同的，呃，
an ex an extra pattern with a different, uh,
以不同的连接连接，嗯，
inch with a different connection to connect the, um,
以不同的方式或者在后面显示某种东西。
two shapes in a different way or to display something in the back.
所以我总是试着不要在前面思考
So I always try not to think just in the front.
有时候最有趣的部分 其实是你没有计划
Sometimes the most interesting part is actually the one that you're not planning
以图案或显示。
to pattern or to display.
还有我之前在网格方面展示的例子
Uh, also the example that I showed before in terms of the grid.
所以有时你可能会，嗯，嗯， 想要创建一个，
So sometimes you might actually, um, um, want to create a,
你有一个更大的床单， 你想只是利用它。
you have a bigger sheet and you want just make use of that.
所以，你可以有像一个
So you can have something like a
小型激光剪线，呃，
small laser cut lines that uh,
可以像游乐场 你只有这种箭
can be like a playground and you have just this kind of arrows that can be
插入以显示 。
insert to display. Like a picture,
就像一个更大的情况 在这个案件中是一个很大的模式。
like a bigger picture in this case was a big pattern.
但你也可以像那些条纹 更像编织技术
But you can also have like on those stripes more like a woven technique
可视化.
visualized.
当然，你还没有材料，但你想做实验。
And of course you don't have material yet, but you want to experiment. I also,
嗯，挑战你玩 玩一点点纸。
um, challenge you to play to play a little bit with paper.
如果哪张纸不行
If which paper doesn't work,
如果纸样连接失败，最终材料也可能失败。[材料词识别不清]
it is not gonna work on oxide because paper is more or less, uh,
类似材料。
similar materials.
所以，无论是灵活性还是属性，嗯，
So either in terms of flexibility or properties is um,
相当相似，很坚硬，厚度差不多
quite similar. It's quite stiff. It's more or less the same thickness. So,
这种设计也能成为我过去的学生的例子
uh, this kind designs can also is an example of my past student who, uh,
两年前在这周里被迷住了 所以她真的做了任务
got covid two years ago during this week. So she actually did assignment, um,
发烧，嗯，通过手， 不是激光切割。
with fever, um, by hands, not the laser cutting.
所以一切都是有可能的 并且可以相互连接
So everything is actually possible and uh, can be interlocked.
当然我们不推荐
Of course we do not recommend it. Um,
但是，这是一个很好的方法， 得到的感觉玩的材料。
but it's uh, a good way to, to get the feeling of playing with material.
当然，你，如果你是有限的 而且你甚至没有，嗯，彩色的纸张，
Of course, you, if you're limited and you don't even have, um, colored paper,
假设你最终会...
let's say you are end up, um,
将小空间涂在两者之间，只是为了区分形状.
coloring the little space in between just to distinguish the shape.
现在还有很多工具，AI和，呃，等等，
Now also there are many tools, AI and, uh, et cetera,
因此，
et cetera that can be incorporated in work workflow. So,
嗯，只是，呃， 非常期待什么，呃，
um, just, uh, very much looking forward to what, uh,
这周你会去探险
you're gonna explore this week.
你永远可以以安全的方式发展
And you can always build upon what's been done in secure fashion
和呃，玩呃， 材料连接。
and uh, play with uh, materials connection.
我有个问题 你刚才说要加入Ai
Uh, I have a question. You just talked about, uh, incorporating ai.
琌或稱
How, um, exactly are you, uh, thinking of that? Just like, uh,
视觉灵感还是什么的
visual inspiration or, or is it something
是的，可以的，比如说，我有个学生 我想，呃，
Yeah, just can be done. For example, I had a student I think, uh,
去年她真的这么做了
last year that she actually did that. Um,
也许可以描述机器，我的屏幕，嗯，在这里。
maybe can describe machine, my screen just um, um, here. Um,
是的，这正是我想的 所以，嗯，
yeah, that's exactly what I was thinking of. So, um,
举例来说，她用的是...
in terms of reference inspiration, for example, she was using, um,
她想用像素艺术做点什么
she wanted to do something in the direction of a pixel art. So she was actually,
尝试通过，嗯，ai，嗯，
um, trying through, um, the ai, um,
获取一些投入，嗯，视觉 她有。
to get some inputs in terms of, um, visuals she had. Um, oh, okay,
好，那可是个好仓库
okay. Great repository for that. Um,
然后她决定不使用，嗯，任何一种。
then she decided not to use actually, um, any of them.
结果实际上是，呃，一些东西，
And the result is actually, uh, something that,
所以在这幻灯片之前，所以
so before in this slide, so
有些人只是使用，嗯，
some people just use, um,
获取更多关于配置或如何不同，嗯，
the tool to get more inputs on the configuration or how different, um,
形状可以重合
shapes mm-hmm. Can be overlapped together. Okay.
当然，如果你看看文件...
To create things. And of course if you look at the documentation also of, um,
以变化论，你有，嗯，
of dine in terms of variations, you have, um,
这是一个很好的构思阶段。好的，谢谢。
a great brainstorming phase. Okay, thank you.
我不知道之前有没有问题
I don't know if there were questions before. Okay. No,
那孩子找牙医，没关系
the kid to the dentist. Um, it's okay.
此会录制，嗯，
This session is recorded and, um,
这是幻灯片，所以你可以了
here's is the slides. So you can already,
对这里的人来说，至少有一个很大的，呃，演示。
for the ones here at least have a big, uh, presentation. Uh,
回到我主人身上，或者，嗯，做我们中的任何一个，嗯，
get back to me on master most or, um, do any of us with, uh,
麻烦，否则，嗯，我们希望你能探索一下
troubles. Otherwise, um, we wish you'll have exploration.
谢谢，谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
再见大家 再见
Bye everyone. Bye.